In this lesson, we'll introduce you to input metrics and explain how we realized their
importance at Amazon and how it changed the way we manage the business.
Jeff and I once visited a Fortune 500 company to meet privately with the CEO in his office.
During our meeting, an assistant dashed in and handed the boss a sheet of paper.
The CEO glanced at it and waved at it and proudly said,
our stock is up 30 cents this morning. He perked up as if he had personally caused the rise.
As we drove to our next meeting, Jeff said, there's nothing the CEO did to cause that 30
cent blip in the stock price. I agreed and added that I wouldn't be surprised if the assistant
had thrown multiple printouts in the recycle bin that morning when the blip wasn't so big.
Would the same scene have played out if the share price had dropped 30 cents?
The more proficient the CEO was, the more likely he would have been to win.
The profound lesson is that share price is what Amazon calls an output metric.
In this chapter, we'll introduce the concept of input metrics, which will enable you to focus
on the activities that drive your business in a meaningful and positive direction.
The CEO I just mentioned and companies in general can rarely sustainably control
output metrics directly. What's important is to focus on the controllable input metrics,
the activities you directly control, which ultimately affect output metrics such as share
price.
Input metrics are controllable and usually customer-facing. Some companies refer to them
as leading indicators. We like to use a stronger term, controllable input metrics. That means it's
a conscious choice you make whether to devote resources, whether those resources are people,
equipment, software, marketing, spending, geographic expansion, or something else,
to move the metrics in the desired direction. Thus, input metrics are things that, when done
right, improve the customer experience, create value, and improve the business.
Input metrics are things that, when done right, improve the business. Thus, input metrics are things that, when done right,
create value, and bring about the desired results in your output metrics like sales, profit, and share price.
Your team's actions, organizational decisions, and where and how you invest money are controllable
inputs. Input metrics are ways to measure the impact and status of all these elements that you
control. Output metrics are lagging indicators. They measure the results of the inputs, which are
leading indicators. Output metrics include financial metrics like revenue, gross profit,
and free cash flow.
As well as metrics like active customers, new subscribers, and churn rate. They're very important,
but they generally can't be directly manipulated in a sustainable way over a long period of time.
Most, but not all, input metrics are customer-facing. Customer-facing input metrics measure factors
that positively improve the customer experience. Factors that make your service or product better,
faster, cheaper, or some combination of all three. Each sustained improvement in the customer
experience creates long-term value for the customer. And that's why input metrics are
for customers. It pays dividends for the next several years. While most input metrics are
customer-facing, many do not directly relate to the customer experience. An example of an input
metric that's not customer-facing and that we paid close attention to at Amazon is inventory
record accuracy, or IRA percentage. 100% inventory record accuracy means that all of the retail
goods, item quantity, and bin location in the fulfillment center perfectly match what's in the
electronic store. So, if you're a customer, you're going to have to pay close attention to the
records of the warehouse management system. When Amazon accepts a customer order, the warehouse
management system must accurately indicate the in-stock status and location, which fulfillment
center, aisle, shelf, and bin location to fulfill the items within the promised delivery date and
time. As a result, a lower IRA percentage will result in a lower rate of on-time order fulfillment,
higher inventory costs, and higher fulfillment costs. Some other examples of input metrics that
are not customer-facing are the inventory record accuracy, or the warehouse management system.
The metrics that are not customer-facing include average days accounts payable,
workplace safety incidents, online marketing dollars spent per month. You may have noticed
that many of these metrics will indirectly affect customers. For example, inventory record accuracy
appears to be a purely operational internal metric. However, when you consider the implications of a
low IRA percentage, not knowing whether you have an item or not, or where it is located,
this would have a significant negative impact on customers.
At Amazon, we took to heart the lesson that we could only forecast and observe our outputs,
but we had a high degree of control over the inputs. This realization was the cumulative
effect of years of operating experience. Our efforts to hit revenue targets at the end of
each quarter and our first few years as a public company firmly informed this.
If we are trending to miss our financial goals as we neared the end of the quarter,
a fire drill would ensue. Finance and category leaders would send frantic emails leading to
meetings to discuss emergency plans to hit our goals. Then teams would scramble to enact these
hastily conceived ideas to boost revenue and profit for the quarter's remaining few weeks.
Most of our activities involved promotions, slashing prices, and getting rid of excess
inventory. Sometimes these promotions provided a small boost to sales, but in most cases,
their real impact was that they distracted us from improving the customer experience,
the long-term driver of growth. We learned that instead of reacting to the
outcomes of our actions, we should be more focused on the results of our actions.
We should focus on controlling the inputs. This approach is one of the reasons why Amazon is now
one of the world's most valuable companies. Every process emits lots of data, whether you
measured or not. Most teams do a good job measuring a process's output. We've noticed
that most people do not do nearly as well measuring their inputs, which means they're
at a disadvantage. In the next few sections, we'll show you how you can define and discover
your inputs. Thanks for watching today. You can follow us on LinkedIn or visit us at
visit our website, workingbackwards.com, to find more content in our library that's part of this course.